Diego Castan, PhD

About

PhD in Machine Learning and Signal Processing

Contact

New York City

Cellphone: +1 650-931-7454

& Email: dcastan@gmail.com

Programming Languages

♥Python Bash, Matlab, C/C++

Machine Learning Tools

PyTorch TensorFlow Sklearn NumPy, SciPy Keras, Kaldi

Specialized Software

Cluster threading: (Sun Grid Engine, Condor) MS Office ETEX

Languages

English, Italian Spanish

Experience

2015-Now SRI International

Menlo Park, CA & NYC, NY

Senior Computer Scientist

- ♦ Applied research for government and commercial R&D efforts in speaker identification and verification, speaker diarization, language identification, calibration and acoustic event detection.
- ♦ Worked with multiple start-ups from SRI Ventures Capital focused in signal and speech processing for health applications.
- ♦ Honored with the outstanding employee award multiple times

2014-2015 **Aragon Research Institute (I3A)**

Zaragoza, Spain

Zaragoza, Spain

Post-doctoral researcher

- ♦ Research topics: Performance of anti-spoofing systems and audio segmentationby-classification approaches
- ♦ Development of a context-aware communicator based on natural language processing and pictograms.

2009-2014 Zaragoza University

PhD. Student

- ♦ Associated to "SD-TEAM: Personalization and autonomous adaptation to the constraints of context in multi-domain spoken dialogue systems".
- ♦ Research topics: Automatic audio content, segmentation and acoustic event detection.
- ♦ Teacher Assistant: Laboratory of "Telecommunications Theory"
- ♦ International internships: Columbia University (NY-USA), Fondazione Brunno Kesslet (Trento-Italy), and SRI International (CA-USA)

2008 Instituto Tecnológico de Aragón (ITA)

Zaragoza, Spain

Engineer

♦ Development of a DGPS in the electronic area.

Education

2009–2014 **Ph.D.** in Speech/Audio Signal Processing, Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition

Thesis: "Advances on Audio Segmentation and Audio Content Description for Multimedia Documents" (Graduated Cum Laude)

Zaragoza University

2008–2009 M.Sc. in Information technology and Radio-Mobility

(Graduated Cum Laude) Zaragoza University

2001–2008 M.Sc. & Bach Electrical Engineering Zaragoza University

1991–2008 **Music Degree** in Classic Guitar Professional Music Conservatory of Zaragoza

Publications

COMPLETE LIST IN GOOGLE SCHOLAR

https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=T5WbJUsAAAAJ&hl=en

Awards, Grants & Honours

2014 **Cum Laude PhD. Thesis** Zaragoza University

2009-2013 **FPI Spanish Government Scholarship** EU and Spanish Government

2009 **Cum Laude M. Sc. Thesis** Zaragoza University